<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500117-28">
               <interp inst="t17500117-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-28" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-28" type="date" value="17500117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500117-28-off123-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-28-defend235 t17500117-28-off123 t17500117-28-verdict126"></join>
         
               <p>141. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-defend235" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Woolfington 
                  <interp inst="t17500117-28-defend235" type="surname" value="Woolfington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-defend235" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-defend235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17500117-28-off123" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-off123" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-off123" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he in a certain field, or open place, near the King's highway, upon 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500117-28-victim237" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Miller 
                        <interp inst="t17500117-28-victim237" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500117-28-victim237" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500117-28-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-28-off123 t17500117-28-victim237"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, five Guineas in Gold, the monies of the said Thomas against his will, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500117-28-cd124" type="crimeDate">Dec. 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-28-off123 t17500117-28-cd124"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person238">
                  Thomas 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person238" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person238" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of Dec. I was coming home from Chelsea, between 7 and 8 in the Evening; at my entrance into the first Five Fields, as they call it, I had Mr. 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person239">
                  Hans 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person239" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person239" type="given" value="Hans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             along with me, he was in liquor and stayed a little behind: I called, Hans, come along; accordingly he did, but very slowly; I went by the <placeName id="t17500117-28-crimeloc125">Crown and Thistle</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500117-28-crimeloc125" type="placeName" value="Crown and Thistle"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500117-28-crimeloc125" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-28-off123 t17500117-28-crimeloc125"></join>, and passed the Fountain; then there are some posts to pass through to enter into another field, but just as I had got through them, and enter'd into the second field, I turned about and called out Hans again: He came slowly after. Then I heard the Footsteps of two or three people; the Ground being very wet, I could hear them step. I believe they came out of the Thistle and Crown, for there was a light as I came by: I said again, come along, Hans, I hear some people coming up. The common path-way was ancle-deep, so I was got upon higher ground, he being in liquor kept the path, and went through the dirt; as near as I can recollect it was about the middle of the field; I was about 20 or 30 yards before him, when I heard some blows struck, but no words. I heard Mr. Fowler say, pray don't murder a poor distressed Sailor ; I saw two or three men with large sticks, beating him as he lay on the ground: Two I can swear to. On my turning my head, the prisoner at the bar came up to me, his particular voice I well know, he said, d - n you, you raseal, you villain, your watch and your money, or I'll cut you to pieces. He had got a large stick in his hand, which I took to be a mop or broom-stick, swinging it over my head, attempting to strike at me: I put myself in a posture of defence, so that he never touch'd my head. I having a slight oak-stick in my hand, kept him off, and desired him to be easy; he found I wanted to make to the low ground, so got between me and that place, swearing, at the same time, he'd cut me to pieces if I did not surrender. When he found I could not escape he came to close quarters : He had got either a sword or a bayonnet, I know not which, but he prick'd me in the forehead ; I fell backwards, and he fell down ; as he fell I heard something chink : He held fast hold of my hand, and I of his waistcoat, by his trembling he seemed as much afraid of me as I was of him. I had five Guineas in one pocket, and some Silver in the other, I put my hand in with an intent to sling down two or three of the Guineas<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175001170012"></xptr> on the ground, knowing they would not easily find them again till the morrow; he catch'd my hand at the same time, and took the five Guineas from me: The others had got my friend all along, so I begg'd he would not hurt me, nor let my friend be murder'd; I told him I had no watch. Then he walk'd as contentedly as any man could do by my side, while I went back and took up my friend. I said my friend had no money; the others, I suppose, heard what I said, and knowing he had got five Guineas of me, made off. My friend was all over dirt, so I went immediately into the Robin-hood and Little-john, being robb'd within about 20 yards of that house. There was the man of the house, and three or four Invalids drinking ; I told them what had happened, saying, if they could make haste and get help, we might take them before they got over the fields. The man of the house seeing the wound on my forehead, said it was done with a bayonnet : His wife fetch'd down a gun; said he, I cannot go without my shoe-buckles, and then he had his bitch to call. We came out with his Candle to see for Mr. Fowler's stick; but they had taken that away with them. They went with me to the Constable's; at the entring of Chelsea, I went through the College, and met with 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person240">
                  Luke 
                  Lidier 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person240" type="surname" value="Lidier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person240" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who knew my tongue; I told him I had been robb'd; I described the person in so particular a manner, to Mr. Harris, who was quite a stranger to me, who came to me on the Thursday morning after, that he said I had no occasion to say any more about it, for he knew the Man that had robb'd me, saying, he had been at his house that evening two or three hours, with two or three foot soldiers, who had put off bad money to him. I can swear to the prisoner's face, by the light of the window at the Robin-hood, and am satisfied he is the man.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person241">
                  Luke 
                  Lidier 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person241" type="surname" value="Lidier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person241" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of December, I was going to London; near eight o'Clock I heard Mr. Miller's Tongue, and said, who's that, Mr. Miller? he had got his handkerchief about his face; I asked him, what was the matter? he told me, he had been robb'd, and advis'd me not to go that way; then came up Mr. Fowler, Sir, said he, do you see how I have been used? I told him, that he had been used very dirtily; he stood upon the Titter-Totter, being in liquor. I went with Mr. Harris to Harp-alley; on the Saturday 7-night, going by Somerset-house, there was a soldier stood century; said Mr. Harris, that is one of the Men who was in company at my house the night Mr. Miller was robb'd; when I got home, I went up to Mr. Babb, and desired him to go and acquaint Mr Miller, that I had saw a Man whom Mr. Harris said was in company with the man who robb'd him that night, at his house: Then Mr. Miller and Mr. Babb came and called upon me, and we all three went to Mr. Harris's. We four went to the Parade, and saw the guards reliev'd; I shewed Mr. Miller the man I saw upon guard; Mr. Miller said, he knew nothing of him. While we was talking, the prisoner was coming along, Mr. Miller said, as soon as he saw him, that is the man who robbed me; Mr. Harris said, that is the man you describ'd to me. Mr. Harris call'd the prisoner to him; Mr. Miller went up to him, and walk'd round him, and said afterwards, he was well satisfied he was the Man. Babb and I followed him to his Lodging, and brought him from thence to an ale-house to Mr. Harris and Mr. Miller.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harris. I have known the prisoner almost three years; he did belong to Ligonier's Horse. On the 19th of December, he came to my house, with four soldiers, and a trumpeter's wife; they were there from between three and four, till seven. When the reckoning came to be paid, the prisoner, and one of the others, began to quarrel; I went between them, and desired them to desist; one of them, 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person242">
                  James 
                  Macdonald 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person242" type="surname" value="Macdonald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person242" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , had a short sword under his arm; he and the prisoner went out together, they stood at the door, and wanted to drink there; then Chelsea Clock struck seven, I heard it. Said Swinney to Macdonald, you had better stay and lie with me to-night, and I would give the prisoner a bed; but they would not stay, so both went away at seven, and I came in after I had took the reckoning, and found I had receiv'd two bad Shillings of the other man. When I had took up that man, and put him in the Savoy, I hearing Mr. Miller had been robb'd, I sent to him, he came and describ'd the prisoner, saying he was no soldier, but there was soldiers in company that knocked him down, and abused his friend; he described the man who robb'd him, thus - He was a lusty young fellow, was inclin'd to sat, with a full fat hand, black shock hair, or a wigg answerable to it; his hand warm withal, and a very coarse voice, and that he was robbed about half an hour after seven o'clock, and said, he believed they came out of the Thistle and Crown - The rest as the last witness, about going to the Park, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence. I have got very good Evidence to prove where I was at that time that night.</p>
               <p>Collonboon. I live at the Thistle and Crown in the Five Fields; the prisoner on the Tuesday before Christmass, came in a little after six o'clock. I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175001170013"></xptr> am positive it was before seven, there was not a living soul came in with him; he was fuddled, and stagger'd against the bar; he remain'd in my house 'till half an hour past nine; there was none in my house but my own family, and I was in company with him all the time; he never went out all the time, but stood on the threshold to make water. I ordered my daughter, at seven o'clock, to put the children to-bed. My brother staid all night, and went away next morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person243">
                  Margaret 
                  Colloxhoon 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person243" type="surname" value="Colloxhoon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person243" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person243" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , his young daughter, deposed, this same night the prisoner came in a little after six o'clock, there was her uncle Henry there, who was going on board a ship, who came to take his leave of them; she said, there was her father, and a man that works at Farmer 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person244">
                  Batt
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person244" type="given" value="Batt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person244" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, his name 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person245">
                  John 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person245" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person245" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             ; that she put the children to bed as the clock struck seven. and left the prisoner in the house when she went up stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person246">
                  John 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person246" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the Crown and Thistle on the Tuesday before Christmas. The prisoner came in about half an hour after six o'clock, or not so much ; there was the man of the house, and his brother; I staid there from before he came in, 'till after he went away, at half an hour past nine, and I went to-bed a little time after; he never was any farther out of the house, than to the threshold, to make water. I never was out of the house all that time. I lodge there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person247">
                  Samuel 
                  Worterbridge 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person247" type="surname" value="Worterbridge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person247" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodg'd at the Thistle and Crown this very night. I am a soldier in the second regiment of guards. I came in a little before eight; I saw the prisoner at the bar, the gentleman of the house, and his brother-in-law, all drinking together. I sat with them 'till half an hour past nine; there was 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person248">
                  John 
                  Jordan 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person248" type="surname" value="Jordan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person248" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in the house; the prisoner was never out at the door in the time.</p>
               <p>Captain 
               <persName id="t17500117-28-person249">
                  Waling
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person249" type="given" value="Waling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person249" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , gave the prisoner the character of a good soldier; and added, he was discharged out of the regiment on his own request; and, after that, made master at arms on board one of his Majesty's vessels.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person250">
                  James 
                  Toose 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person250" type="surname" value="Toose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person250" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a green-grocer, said, he never knew any ill of him, and had known him six months.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person251">
                  Anthony 
                  Courtley 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person251" type="surname" value="Courtley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person251" type="given" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said, he had known him from his infancy, and that he's a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person252">
                  Lewis 
                  Longfield 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person252" type="surname" value="Longfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person252" type="given" value="Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , has known him five years, said, he's an honest, upright man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person253">
                  Thomas 
                  Lampier 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person253" type="surname" value="Lampier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person253" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , said, he knew the prisoner six or seven years, and that he's a very honest man, lov'd and caress'd by all his officers, and esteem'd by all his brother soldiers.</p>
               <p>This being the soldier who the prisoner came to in the park, was asked, what he said to Mr. Harris on the affair? he answer'd. Mr. Harris told been there had been such people robb'd ; and the man had describ'd the person so and so; said, by the description given, it seemed as if he was the man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Harris. This Witness said, at that time, he believed they were both guilty; for they looked very blank, (meaning the prisoner, and another soldier) and this witness was one of the company that night drinking with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person254">
                  Luke 
                  Lidier 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person254" type="surname" value="Lidier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person254" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , deposed, he heard Lampler say the same; that is, he believed the prisoner and Macdonald were guilty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-28-person255">
                  James 
                  Keene 
               <interp inst="t17500117-28-person255" type="surname" value="Keene"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person255" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Robin-hood. The prosecutor came into my house about seven o'clock that night: he had a little sprinkle of blood on his left eye. I asked him, what was the matter? He said, he had been robb'd of five Guineas. I was slipshoe'd, and ask'd him, if I should put up my shoes and pursue them? He told me, it was not much matter; saying, he believed they were gone. The man along with him was a little in liquor; who said, he had lost a cane or stick; he desired me to let him have a piece of candle, and go out to see if he could find it, where he had been robb'd. We went to the place ; then he desired me to see him as far as Chelsea, which I did, with my servant my Dog, and my Gun. We saw him as far as the Constable's, there he called for a pint of twopenny, and gave my man twopence; the place was about fifty or sixty yards from my house. It is impossible the prosecutor should see the prisoner's face there by the light of my window.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The place where we went to look for the stick, was the place where Mr. Fowler was robb'd; and the place where I was robb'd, was about half-way between that place, and this man's house: I being before Mr. Fowler, at that time.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500117-28-verdict126" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-verdict126" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500117-28-punish127" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500117-28-punish127" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-28-defend235 t17500117-28-punish127"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>