<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17500117-15">
               <interp inst="t17500117-15" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-15" type="year" value="1750"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-15" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17500117"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17500117-15" type="date" value="17500117"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17500117-15-off63-c91" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-15-defend125 t17500117-15-off63 t17500117-15-verdict66"></join>
         
               <p>126. 
               
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-defend125" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17500117-15-defend125" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-defend125" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-defend125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17500117-15-off63" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-off63" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-off63" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, val. 7 l. the goods of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17500117-15-victim127" type="victimName">
                           Isaac 
                           Kennish 
                        <interp inst="t17500117-15-victim127" type="surname" value="Kennish"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500117-15-victim127" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17500117-15-victim127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-15-off63 t17500117-15-victim127"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling house
            </rs> of the said 
               <persName id="t17500117-15-person128">
                  Isaac 
                  Kennish 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person128" type="surname" value="Kennish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person128" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500117-15-cd64" type="crimeDate">December 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-15-off63 t17500117-15-cd64"></join>.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-person129">
                  Isaac 
                  Kennish 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person129" type="surname" value="Kennish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person129" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17500117-15-crimeloc65">sign of the Hampshire Hog, in St. Luke's parish</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17500117-15-crimeloc65" type="placeName" value="sign of the Hampshire Hog, in St. Luke's parish"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17500117-15-crimeloc65" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17500117-15-off63 t17500117-15-crimeloc65"></join>; the prisoner, a woman whose name is 
               <persName id="t17500117-15-person130">
                  Judith 
                  Dyke 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person130" type="surname" value="Dyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person130" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person130" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17500117-15-person131">
                  Philip 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person131" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person131" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came into my house on the 11th of Dec. about 9 o'clock at night, they called for a tankard of beer: I having but two silver tankards, and they both in use at that time, I ordered my servant to draw them a full pot of beer. I had a club in the next room; I came out for a pen and ink, I saw all my company was gone into that room, and they had left a silver tankard upon the table, near the Prisoner, who stood with his back towards it, and the rest of his company were sitting by the fire, the windows were shut up, and I went back in the other room; they went away at the door that leads to the street; after this my girl called me, and said the man is gone away with your tankard.</p>
               <p>The other witness (Warwick) staid, who told me he could not go away, for that man, meaning the Prisoner, has took away something with him, either pewter or silver, like a tankard; and likewise said, he told 
               <persName id="t17500117-15-person132">
                  Judith 
                  Dyke 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person132" type="surname" value="Dyke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person132" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person132" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that he and she should come into trouble about it; adding, she made a pish at it: I sent my young man one way, and I went another, but we could not find the prisoner, or the woman. Warwick still abode in the house, nor did he endeavour to get away; saying, he would stay with all his heart: then I sent for the constable of the night, and Warwick was taken into custody. I had seen the woman before, and a person gave me intelligence where she lived; I went to her house, and there was a man made answer and said, she was not at home; (we could hear her whisper ) I went back again, and we carried Warwick to New-prison; my lodger said when we came back, if I would go down to the woman, she would open the door to me; he was drinking with them that night in my house, but he has hid himself, and I cannot find him; I fear the woman has sent him out of the way; we went again, and he knocked, and she immediately let him in, and the constable took charge of her; the justice thought proper to admit her to bail. I never saw the tankard since. We searched Warwick to see if he had any knife, or such instruments about him, and I am sure he could not have the tankard about him: the justice admitted Warwick to bail, and upon Thursday evening he took the Prisoner, and sent for me, and he was secured; they went away between 8 or 9 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="175001170005"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-person133">
                  Phillip 
                  Warwick 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person133" type="surname" value="Warwick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person133" type="given" value="Phillip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of Dec. last as I was going along Cheapside. I met the Prisoner, I had not seen him for 4 or 5 Years; he said to me, shall we not drink together ? I said with all my heart. Said I, I'll go to the Hercules and Pillars, in Bow-lane. No, said he, I'll go to a friend at the bottom of Bread-street. We went there, and Mrs. Dyke rapp'd at the sash window, at the Bull's-head: We went in, and drank 7 or 8 Tankards of beer. Said she, I have money to receive of a man who is to meet me at the Hampshire-hog, in Goswell-street. I went with the prisoner and her there, and they staid till about 8 or 9 o'clock; they pretended to play at cards, and after that there came in a man, whom, she said, she was to receive some money of, his name is Hosier, (the person the prosecutor mentioned, who is gone out of the way.) They talked to themselves some time. The company that was at the fire mov'd from it, and we went to it, all but the prisoner at the bar, who kept his place behind the door, on the left hand: This was about an hour before they went away. When the beer came about, he said, he did not care to drink; by and bye I heard liquor spill, I turn'd and saw something like a tankard in his hand, and he cover'd it under the right hand flap of his coat; it was about half cover'd: Presently I heard liquor spill again. I went betwixt the woman, and the man of whom she was to receive money, and whisper'd them, saying, I feared we should come into trouble, for, I thought, he was going to steel away a tankard. She said, pshaw, pshaw. The man made no answer. At going away the woman went first out at the door, and I second, the prisoner after me; he had his left hand under his coat, with something like a pot or a tankard in that hand: I turn'd back at the door, and said, I must speak with this man, meaning Hosier ; but the prisoner laid hold of the skirt of my coat, and said, come along, you have no business with that man I am sure. I told Hosier the prisoner had got a tankard under his coat, or something like it. Said Hosier to the Girl, see if there be any thing missing ? Said I, it will be the best way to go, in the first place, after the man. The Constable was sent for, and I desired he would be so good as to go and take the woman, thinking she would not deny what I whisper'd to her, of my suspicion about the prisoner. The Friday following I took the prisoner in Bedford-court, coming down to Covent-garden: I did not charge him with the thing then, because I had heard of his Character; so I took him to a public house, sent for a constable, charg'd him, and sent for the Prosecutor.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-person134">
                  Richard 
                  Ansey 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person134" type="surname" value="Ansey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person134" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Constable, I was sent for the night the prosecutor was robb'd. Warwick seemed to be in some great concern, that the other man was not domin d, and said, he believed if the woman was taken, very likely the prisoner and tankard might be met with again; he likewise mentioned his whispering the woman, as mentioned before, and likewise of Stevens's spilling the beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-person135">
                  Philip 
                  Slackman 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person135" type="surname" value="Slackman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person135" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a watchman, who came with the constable, confirm'd what the constable said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17500117-15-person136">
                  John 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17500117-15-person136" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with the prosecutor; I was in the room the best part of the time; they had paid 13 d. half-penny, and there was three half-pence to pay; the woman told me Mr. Hosier would do that; then they went into another box, that is, Warwick, Hosier, and the woman; the prisoner stood where he did before, and I saw the tankard close behind him: The prisoner said he would not go away without another pot of beer, and bid me draw it; Mr. Warwick was then for going without any more; I drew a pot of beer, and carry'd it to the prisoner: He said, young man I am drunk, I can't drink any more; he sat down, saying, I must give it to the company, adding he was sick. I sat down with my back to the prisoner, and heard something spill; I thought somebody had been spewing, or there was water running; the others sat by the fire at this time. I did not see the tankard then, nor have I seen it since I saw it standing behind his back. When I heard it I look'd round, and look'd hard at the prisoner, and he look'd hard at me; then Mr. Warwick call'd for another pot of beer, and I heard beer spill again: then there were 7 d. half penny to pay, the prisoner desired the woman to pay for him, and he would pay her again. I saw Mr. Warwick whisper the woman, and she gave her head a shake, and look'd back; but what she said I cannot tell: And likewise heard Warwick tell Hosier as before mentioned, when the Prisoner was gone out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any beer in the tankard when it stood behind the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Butler. I cannot tell my Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17500117-15-verdict66" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17500117-15-verdict66" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>